Hey everybody, welcome back. This is the
three question series with AMR. I am
Chris Gordon and I have someone with me
today who has been working very very
hard not just in her job but somewhere
else. I want to introduce to you Kathy
Kathy Clow and if you could just tell us
some things about your family, where you
are and what you are almost finished
with.
>> Yeah. So I mean my favorite thing to
tell everybody is that I'm a grandma to
almost five. We have three outside of
the womb and two inside of the womb. But
um my husband John and I have four
children. They're all married. Um now
we're having grandbabies.
Um so that is of all of my roles and
titles and whatever job I do. That's
that's my absolute favorite.
>> That's your best paid role.
>> That's the best. We are avid coffee
drinkers and um yeah, loving love being
outside and going and doing. And so
that's a really quick nutshell about
about us. Um, we're currently in Texas.
Normally we reside in Honduras. Um, but
currently in Texas because I am at the
very very end of completing a degree in
mental health counseling with an
emphasis in marriage and family therapy.
So I have five weeks to go. Lord
willing. I pass this last class and I
get to graduate.
>> Lord willing. Yes. Yes. Five weeks.
Okay. So I would love to hear in the
midst of all that you what's the little
corner of the kingdom that you are
vocationally like employed getting paid
to be in and do in the kingdom right
now.
>> Yeah, that is a really really new uh
endeavor. Um my little kingdom corner
used to be um just kind of Central
America. My husband is the regional
director for Mission to the World for
Central America and Mexico and um I came
alongside of him and helping him just
love on our missionaries there um
support them, encourage them. Kind of
was in a member care role for Central
America, which is why I did this degree
in marriage and family therapy to just
have the education, the development for
self to know how to care well for our
missionaries. And then during this time
of um grad school, NTW created a brand
new position. Um I was actually on the
committee that helped create the
position and now often think I would
have spoken up a whole lot more had I
known [laughter] what God was going to
ask of me. I think I would have been a
little more bold and vocal. Um but two
years ago a position called women's
development coordinator was created and
I was shortly as a after asked to
consider the position of which I said
no.
>> Um the Lord called me into counseling
and no. And then I took about nine
months of arguing with the Holy Spirit
until
he made it very clear that I was
supposed to say yes.
>> You're going to lose Kathy. I'm so
>> I know I've been there. You would think
at 51 I would know you don't argue with
the Holy Spirit, but somehow I still do
anyway. Uh so yeah, the the very day
that I saw my first client in
internship, I got offered the position
um officially.
So the agreement was I could get to
finish grad school first and slow on
board. Um so my little corner of
ministry is the globe. It's [laughter]
it's um just really caring for um the
women in our organization, working to
develop them. Um you know, as as the
Lord does, he does nothing by happen
stance. Um as I've been developing
myself and going from, you know, a
stay-at-home mom that bakes bread and
hosts teams um and loves on babies to
becoming this professional in
counseling. Um, I think it's just one
more experience that the Lord allowed me
to walk through so I could um have that
personal connection with other women in
our organization that are like, "Hey,
the Lord's calling me into calling me
into this. What do I do? How do I do
it?" And so, um, just really thankful
and gracious to see the faithfulness of
the Lord um, and equipping me as I I
step into this role that I have no idea
where it's going to go.
>> Yeah. So, I'd love to hear stories. I'd
love to hear all the stories, but we
probably have time for one story of
where you've seen God working even
lately.
>> Yeah, I was, you know, in preparation
for this talking to my husband, like
it's so hard because in counseling, I
can't give details of stories and and
even in working with missionaries and
and the things that we do. But what I
will say just in kind of as general as
possible, um the Lord gave me the
opportunity to really work with a lot of
couples in internship and I really I
love that. Um I think if our marriages
are strong then our families are going
to be strong. And so just seeing that I
as a broken vessel can be used by the
Holy Spirit um in restoration of
marriages I think was a really neat
thing to watch and observe. Just seeing
um seeing a wife in deep repentance to
her husband and seeing that um
seeing that then walk through in
restoration of their marriage. Um, and
so that's kind of like my counseling
corner that I see.
>> Um, and just love and just fell in love
with with sitting with couples. Um,
>> and then as far as in my new role is I'm
just onboarding with it. Really haven't
done a ton
to um form my advisory team. And then
the most exciting thing I think right
now is I'm working with CDM with Karen
Hodgej and doing a partnership between
CDM and MTW and how we can bring
disciplehip resources to the globe and
to our women internationals. So that's
>> yes
>> kind of where I see God working.
>> That's wonderful.
>> Sorry, I know that was two stories and
you told me one.
>> No, no, no, no, no. Don't [laughter] you
want the stories. We want the stories.
Yeah. And you have what a fabulous
vantage point you have. you know that
most of us don't in terms of like all
these places God is working and what it
looks like and the details and the big
and the little like what a great seat he
gave you.
>> It's been really it's been really cool
and I geography is not a strong point
for me.
>> Yeah.
>> And I told um our resource reps in the
MTW office and they're the ones that
kind of keep us all in line. I said I'm
just going to come into the office.
We're going to get a world map and you
guys are just going to like teach me.
>> That's right. That's great. So what
Okay. So, keeping in mind all that you
have your finger in,
>> yeah,
>> what can we the rest the your brothers
and sisters in PTA, how can we encourage
you in what you do like on a in a
specific and a general way?
>> Yeah. Um, well, I just as all
missionaries do, um, not only are we
stateates for me to finish up my
internship, but we're also on our home
ministry assignment and raising support.
So, pray that the Lord would provide
resources. We have been with MTW almost
25 years and he's been faithful.
>> Wow.
>> Um so yeah, just pray that the Lord
would um we're we're anxious to get back
to the field um to get although I'm
loving being in the States and close to
grandchildren. Um you know, we're it's
been almost two years, year and a half.
Um and then really a very specific way I
myself am building my library of
resources for women's ministry, for
women's development, for women's
leadership.
>> Um and I'm not well verssed. So, if
anybody has any great book
recommendations, things that a must have
that I should have in my library, please
email me. Send me
>> Yes, which is where your email is. What?
Just tell us right now.
>> It is kathy.cloudmtw.org.
So, katy.wmtw.org.
>> mtw.org. You can send them right to her
and take them places. Yes. So, good.
It's exciting and it's it I will look
forward to hearing and we get um MTW
emails and in whatever way it comes to
just more and more of what you're doing
and how it goes. So, thank you. Thank
you for
>> telling us what's happening. Yeah. God
bless your ministry.
>> Thank you so much.